Listen to a short talk on biology.
Now the Australia jumping spider as you can image got its name for its ability to leap.
But it can swim too.
What’s most interesting though is its ability to use try
and error tactics when solving problems.
Now the jumping spider attacks and eats other spiders.
It’ll sit at the edge of another spider's web and attract the spider by
tapping out different signals to mimic the struggles of a trapped insect
and it’ll keep changing the signals till successfully lured its prey out.
Well, to see if the jumping spider could apply the same problem solving technique, try
and error to unfamiliar situations, scientists conducted an experiment.
They field a trap full of water and then put some sand in the
middle, like an island.
In between the island and the edge of the trap, they put a rock.
When they put the spider on the island, some tried jumping to the rock,
and some tried swimming.
All the spiders that successfully reached the rock either by jumping
or by swimming use the same method to make it from the rock to
the edge of the tree.
If the spider failed to reach the rock, it was placed back on the
island,
but the next time they try to leave, spiders did opposite of whatever didn’t
work the first time, leaping if it had swum,
or swimming if it had leaped.
So we see the spiders using the same try and error in crossing the
water as they used in hunting.